Finding Aid for Raymond W. Waggoner Papers 1926-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Raymond W. Waggoner Papers
1926-1977
Waggoner, Raymond W. (Raymond Walter), 1901-2000.
Neuropsychiatrist, professor of psychiatry and chair of the department at the University of Michigan. Professional papers, chairman's files of department of psychiatry.
85454 Aa 2
15.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Raymond W. Waggoner (donor no. 6921 ) in May 1983. Some additional material was received from Waggoner's daughter in 2002.
The collection is open for research, except for patient files and miscellaneous personnel and student files.
The Wagoner papers include restricted material in the following categories:
Personnel Related Records -- Box 16
Student Academic Records -- Box 6, 16
Patient/Client Records -- Box 16
Raymond W. Waggoner was chairman of the University of Michigan Department of Psychiatry from 1937 until his retirement in 1970. At the heart of his diverse interests was the belief that the causes and cures for mental diseases had both biological and psychological bases. This view is now widely accepted, but when Waggoner entered the profession, his interest in the neuroscientific aspects of psychiatric treatment was unusual. Under his direction the Department of Psychiatry developed programs which successfully integrated neuroscience into its clinical and educational programs. Waggoner's other professional interests included child and adolescent psychiatry, mental health issues relating to military service, human sexuality, and community mental health.
Born in Carson City, Michigan on August 2, 1901, Waggoner took his undergraduate and medical training at the University of Michigan. He earned his M.D. degree in 1924, and a Doctor of Science degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1930. He originally planned to be a neurosurgeon, however when he joined the University of Michigan neurology faculty in 1929 he became heavily involved in treating patients who had been referred from the State Psychopathic Hospital. At first, he helped colleagues interpret the Freudian terms on these patients' charts, but he progressed quickly to providing treatment for many of the mentally ill patients at the University Hospital.
While in England on sabbatical in 1936, Waggoner was offered the post of chairman of the University of Michigan Department of Psychiatry. The offer was a surprise to him, but his interest in the biological sources of mental illness as well as psychoanalysis made him attractive to medical school administrators. Their goal was to develop a psychiatry department with diverse clinical and research strengths, which would be a leader in integrating a variety of approaches to the treatment of mental illnesses. Waggoner proved able to do this, and took the lead in bringing major research and treatment centers to Michigan. He lobbied to change state laws governing treatment of mentally ill patients, and this led to the 1939 opening of the Neuropsychiatric Institute, which replaced the old State Psychopathic Hospital. He also helped establish the Child Psychiatry Hospital in 1955, and the Mental Health Research Institute (MHRI) in 1960.
Waggoner's activities extended well beyond the University of Michigan. He was active in the American Psychiatric Association (APA), the American Medical Association (AMA) and many other professional associations. During World War II, he served as an adviser to the Selective Service, and developed a psychiatric test which was used to determine draftees' mental fitness for military service. After the war, Waggoner worked with the U.S. Surgeon General's office, studying the effects of postwar occupation on Japan and Germany, and also gave advice about easing veterans' transition to civilian life. The latter led to the creation of the Veterans' Readjustment Center in Ann Arbor in 1946. On the local level, Waggoner was concerned about the availability of community mental health services, and he helped establish the Community Mental Health Center of Washtenaw County in 1966. He also played a role in organizing a medical assistant training program at Cleary College in Ypsilanti.
After his retirement from the Department of Psychiatry in 1970, Waggoner remained professionally active. He was a psychiatric consultant for the Masters and Johnson Institute studies in human sexuality, regularly worked at his office on campus, and continued to treat patients until he was well into his eighties. Waggoner died in 2000.
The Raymond W. Waggoner papers comprise 15.5 linear feet, and have been divided into six series: Biographical Information; Topical Files; Papers and Addresses; Correspondence; Photographs; and Awards, Honors, Certificates. The collection documents his research and professional activities and, to some extent, his teaching and administrative work in the Department of Psychiatry.
Subjects:
American Psychiatric Association.; Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry.; Psychiatry.; Psychiatrists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Reproductive Biology Research Foundation (U.S.); University of Michigan. Children's Psychiatric Hospital.; University of Michigan. Department of Psychiatry.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Mental Health Research Institute.; University of Michigan. Neuropsychiatric Institute.; Waggoner, Raymond W. (Raymond Walter), 1901-2000.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biographical Information
  Biographical Information (2 folders; 1926-1977) contains curricula vitae, clippings, and daily diaries which provide information about Waggoner's educational background, professional activities, association memberships and publications.
  - Curricula Vitae and Clippings, 1926-1977 (Box 1)
  - Daily Diaries, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
- Topical Files
  Topical Files (7.8 linear ft; 1937-1976) are arranged alphabetically, and contain correspondence, memoranda, reports and meeting minutes. The series is diverse, and reflects Waggoner's many professional interests. He was active in a variety of professional associations, and the Topical Files include records regarding the American Medical Association (AMA), the American Psychiatric Association (APA), the Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry (GAP), the Michigan Society of Neurology and Psychiatry (MSNP), and the Reproductive Biology Research Institute; the latter is more commonly known as the Masters and Johnson Institute. Waggoner also kept topical files about psychiatric units at the University of Michigan. There are extensive files on the Children's Psychiatric Hospital, the Mental Health Research Institute, the Neuropsychiatric Institute, and the Department of Psychiatry. There is some overlap between the contents of the Topical Files and Correspondence series, so researchers should check both series for material on any given topic or organization.
  - Alabama at Birmingham, University of, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1964 (Box 1)
  - American College of Psychiatrists
    - General, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - The Dean Award, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - American Fund for Psychiatry, 1954-1969 (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association (AMA)
    - Association of Medical Colleges Report, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Medical Education Accreditation, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Residency Training Reviews, 1947-1961 (Box 1)
    - Survey of Training Programs, 1965 (Box 1)
  - American Neurological Association: "Liver Disease and Brain Pathology,", 1965 (Box 1)
  - American Psychiatric Association (APA)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Conflicts in Psychiatry, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Outpatient Clinics, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
    - American Hospital Association (AHA)
      - Community Health Centers, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
      - Film, "Psychiatric Services in General Hospitals,", 1962-1966 (Box 1)
      - Liaison Committee, 1956-1973; 11 folders (Box 1)
      - Liaison Committee Brochure, "Psychiatric Services in General Hospitals,", 1960-1961 (Box 1)
      - Psychiatric Units in General Hospitals, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
    - Building Fund, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - Central Inspection Board, 1955-1958 (Box 2)
    - Committee on National Defense, 1957-1960 (Box 2)
    - Committee on Psychiatry in Medical Education, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1970; 9 folders (Box 2)
    - Divisional Meeting in Detroit, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Educational Council for Foreign Medical Graduates, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Japanese Psychiatric Society Meeting, 1963 (Box 2)
    - "Perspectives for the APA Under the New Constitution,", 1968 (Box 2)
    - St. Louis Meeting, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Session on Psychiatry and Academic Education, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Statement on Psychology Certification, 1953-1958 (Box 2)
    - Symposium on Neuroses, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Col. William H., 1962-1970 (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor Council of Veterans' Affairs, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - Casework
    - Board of Veterans' Appeals, 1965-1969 (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2069 ]
    - Ireland, Thomas (attorney) re: Magras Case, 1965-1967; 3 folders (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2067 ]
  - Center for Forensic Psychiatry, 1974 (Box 16)
    [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2074 ]
  - Central Neuropsychiatric Association, 1954-1967 (Box 2)
  - Cerebral Palsy Project, 1951-1961 (Box 2)
  - Chaplain/ Pastoral Counseling, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Child Care, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Children's Psychiatric Hospital
    - General, 1956-1960 (Box 2)
    - Planning Committee, 1953-1956 (Box 2)
  - Civil Service Commission of Michigan, 1945-1955 (Box 2)
  - Clinical Psychiatry Course with Dr. Frohlich, 1938-1941 (Box 2)
  - Comprehensive Textbook of Psychiatry, 1965-1968; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Dean Awards, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Electroencephalography Laboratory, 1951-1962 (Box 2)
  - Electroshock Therapy, 1941-1947 (Box 2)
  - Emotionally Disturbed Children Conference, 1953 (Box 2)
  - European Trip, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Germany, 1949-1957 (Box 2)
  - Graduate Psychiatric Education Conference, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry (GAP)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1961; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1966; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Homosexuality, 1950-1954; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Military Preventive Psychiatry, 1954-1961 (Box 3)
    - Psychiatric Illness in Political Figures, 1962; 2 folders (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2062 ]
    - Sex and the College Student, 1965 (Box 3)
  - History of Neuropsychiatry in World War II (Ivan Berlien and RWW), circa 1959 (Box 3)
  - Human Sexuality Seminar, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Hypnosis, 1960-1969 (Box 16)
  - Insulin Therapy, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - International Congress on Mental Health, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
  - Ionia State Hospital
    - Correspondence, 1954-1966 (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2066 ]
    - Special Committee, 1964-1966; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Joint Committee for Stroke Facilities, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Journal of Abstracts, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Kalamazoo State Hospital, 1955-1966 (Box 3)
  - Kresge Building Committee, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Lafayette Clinic, 1954-1969 (Box 3)
  - Lansing Appointments, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Medical Class of 1924 Reunion, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Mental Health Research Institute (MHRI)
    - General, 1955-1960; 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Background Material, 1956-1960 (Box 3)
    - Behavioral Science Journal, 1956; undated (Box 3)
    - Dedication, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    - McGregor Fund, 1951-1960 (Box 3)
    - Organization, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
    - Personnel Policy, 1958 (Box 4)
    - Staff Applicants, 1957-1959 (Box 4)
  - Michigan
    - Association of Professions (MAP), 1959-1960 (Box 4)
    - Boys Vocational School, 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - Coldwater State Home and Training School, 1944-1956 (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2056 ]
    - Community Mental Health Centers Task Force, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Crippled Children's Commission, 1946-1956 (Box 4)
    - Department of Corrections-Jackson Prison, 1953-1967 (Box 4)
    - Department of Health
      - Acting Director, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Meeting of Probate Judges, 1958 (Box 4)
    - Department of Mental Health
      - General, 1958-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Children's Centers, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
      - Commission, 1945-1946; 3 folders (Box 16)
        [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2046 ]
    - Epilepsy Center and Association, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
    - Governor's Conference, Mental Health Session, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Legislature-Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 4)
    - Nursing Center Assoc. Spec. Com., Psychiatric Nursing, 1950-1954 (Box 4)
    - Society for Mental Health, 1947-1970; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Society of Neurology and Psychiatry (MSNP)
      - General, 1938-1965; 4 folders (Box 4)
      - Award Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
      - Committee on Commitment Procedures, 1943-1944 (Box 4)
      - Committee on Traumatic Neurosis, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
      - Conference on Psychiatry and War, 1942-1945 (Box 5)
      - Long-term Planning Committee, 1959-1965 (Box 5)
      - Mental Disease Law Changes, 1938-1955 (Box 16)
        [SR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2038 ]
      - Selection of Men for the Armed Forces, circa 1942-1943 (Box 5)
    - Society of Pastoral Care, 1946-1970; 7 folders (Box 5)
    - State Board of Registration in Medicine, 1955-1963 (Box 5)
    - State Medical Society
      - General, 1949-1966; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Certification of Psychologists, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
      - Clinical Institute, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Committee on Psychiatric Units in General Hospitals, 1959-1961 (Box 5)
      - Journal Review, 1960 (Box 5)
      - Mental Health Committee
        - General, 1955-1962; 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Definitions of Psychotherapy, 1953-1958 (Box 5)
      - Panel on Headaches, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Military Psychiatry, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Military Psychiatry: Combat Fatigue, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Milwaukee Sanitarium, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Nassau Neuropsychiatric Society, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - National Board of Medical Examiners, 1962-1968; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene-Research on Dementia Praecox, 1935-1941; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - National Research Council Symposium on Preventive and Social Psychiatry, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Neuropathology Laboratory, 1950-1961 (Box 6)
  - Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI)
    - Administrative Committee Notes, 1937 (Box 6)
    - Alumni, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
    - Budget Information, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
    - Building Committee, 1937-1939 (Box 6)
    - Building Dedication, 1939 (Box 6)
    - Early Developments and Arrangements, 1937 (Box 6)
    - Executive Committee, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Histories, 1919-1960 (Box 6)
    - History of Rules and Regulations, 1964; undated (Box 6)
    - Outpatient Building, 1948-1951 (Box 6)
    - Residents, former, circa 1962 (Box 6)
    - Resident Lists, 1937-1961 (Box 6)
    - Staff Assignment Sheets (incomplete), 1932-1962 (Box 6)
    - Staff Meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
    - Staff Worksheets, 1937-1961 (Box 6)
  - New Jersey Psychiatric Association, 1961 (Box 6)
  - New Orleans Graduate Medical Assembly, 1941-1942 (Box 6)
  - Niehuss, Marvin L., 1958-1965 (Box 6)
  - Northville State Hospital
    - General, 1948-1968 (Box 6)
    - Accreditation, 1974 (Box 6)
  - "On Becoming a College Student"-RWW's comments, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Opler, Marvin K., 1957-1961 (Box 6)
  - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic, 1961-1969 (Box 6)
  - Pittsburgh, University of
    - General, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Lecture, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Pontiac State Hospital, 1954-1963 (Box 6)
  - Premature Ejaculation Treatment, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Privileged Communication, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Probate Judges-Change in Statute, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Psychiatric Evaluation of Applicants for Pilot Licenses, 1958-1962 (Box 6)
  - Rabinovitch, Ralph, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Reproductive Biology Research Foundation (RBRF)
    - General, circa 1960s (Box 6)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Continuing Education Program: Interviews and Training, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
    - Conversations with Other Doctors, transcribed, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 7 folders (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 16)
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2071 ]
    - Grant Applications, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Post Graduate Medicine, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Requests for Funds, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Research Proposal: Effects of Institutional Isolation, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Sex Therapy Clinics, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - "Sexual Dysfunction in Middle Life,", 1973 (Box 7)
    - Training, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Retirement, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Roche Report, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
  - Russia: Reports and Notes on 1961 Trip, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Sabbatical, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Schizophrenia and Psychopharmacology Joint Research Project
    - General, 1957-1965; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Meetings, 1957-1963; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Schizophrenia Research Findings, undated (Box 7)
  - Seitz, Charles, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Selective Service-National Headquarters, 1944-1947; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Selective Service-State of Michigan, 1940-1945; 2 folders (Box 16)
    [CR RESTRICTED until January 1, 2045 ]
  - Sex Education, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Sex Education and Marriage Counseling, 1965-1967 (Box 8)
  - Sexual Behavior, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Social Security Administration Correspondence, 1963 (Box 8)
  - State of Michigan-Compensation for Mental Health Workers, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - State Psychopathic Hospital
    - Budget, 1936-1938 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 8)
  - Testosterone Research Project, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Traverse City State Hospital, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan
    - Committee on Sex Education in Medical Schools, 1964-1966 (Box 8)
    - Department of Psychiatry
      - Annual Reports, 1959-1962 (Box 8)
      - Masters Degree in Psychiatry, 1938-1947 (Box 8)
      - Part-time Appointments, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
    - Medical School
      - General, 1939-1949; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Budget, 1936-1938 (Box 8)
      - Dean's Committee on Psychiatric Training and Research, 1956-1962; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Veterans Service Bureau, 1944-1946 (Box 8)
  - University of Tennessee School of Social Work, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Veterans Administration (Washington), 1947-1957 (Box 8)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital of Ann Arbor, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Council on Aging, 1972-1976 (Box 8)
  - Western Reserve University Talk, 1972 (Box 8)
- Papers and Addresses
  The series Papers and Addresses (1.6 linear ft.) is arranged chronologically and contains virtually all of Waggoner's written work between 1926 and 1973. This series provides perhaps the most vivid picture of his eclectic interests, and of the ways in which those interests changed and developed over the course of his career.
  - 1926
    - A Case of Epilepsy... (Box 9)
    - A Case Sweating Localized... (Box 9)
  - 1927
    - Encephalography (Box 9)
  - 1928
    - Thrombosis of the Superior Cerebral Vein (Box 9)
  - 1929
    - Extraneural and Neural Anomalies in Friedreich's Ataxia (Box 9)
    - Hemianopsia and Visual Hallucinations (Box 9)
    - Schilder's Disease (Box 9)
    - Tumors of the Occipital Lobe (Box 9)
    - Personality Studies in Children...Chorea Cases (Box 9)
  - 1930
    - Development of Plantar Reflex in Children (Box 9)
  - 1931
    - Sydenham's Chorea (Box 9)
    - Technique of Encephalography (Box 9)
    - A New Position Used in Encephalography (Box 9)
  - 1932
    - Friedreich's Ataxia ... (Box 9)
    - Critical Study of a Case of Aphasia (Box 9)
    - Cisterna Puncture (Box 9)
  - 1933
    - Konzentrische Klerose (Box 9)
  - 1934
    - Familial Organic Psychosis (Box 9)
    - Encephalography under Nitrous Oxide Anesthesia (Box 9)
  - 1935
    - Unclassified Organic Psychosis (Box 9)
    - A Clinico-Pathologic Study of Astrocytomas (Box 9)
  - 1936
    - Destruction of the Cerebral Cortex Following Nitrous Oxide ... (Box 9)
    - Diagnosis of Brain Tumors (Box 9)
    - The Pharmacopoeia and the Physician (Box 9)
    - The Interpretation of Encephalograms (Box 9)
  - 1938
    - Hereditary Cerebellar Ataxia (Box 9)
  - 1939
    - Gross Pathology of the Oligodendrogliomas (Box 9)
    - Bromide Intoxication (Box 9)
  - 1940
    - Statistical Study of Lead in Human Blood and Urine (Box 9)
  - 1941
    - Juvenile Aberrant Sexual Behavior (Box 9)
    - Role of Trauma in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (Box 9)
    - Mental Hygiene/ Convulsive Disorders (Box 9)
  - 1942
    - Sex Linked Hereditary Nystagmus (Box 9)
    - Agenesis of the White Matter with Idiocy (Box 9)
    - Wilson's Disease ... (Box 9)
  - 1943
    - Anatomic and Pathologic Considerations in Convulsive Disorders (Box 9)
    - Relationship Between Emotional Factors and Rheumatoid Arthritis (Box 9)
    - Genealogic and Clinicopathologic Study of Pick's Disease (Box 9)
    - Simultaneous Intra-and Inter-Twin Electroencephalogram (Box 9)
    - Pick's Disease (Box 9)
  - 1944
    - Psychiatric Selection of Men for the Armed Forces (Box 9)
    - Non-Structural Cerebrovascular Disease as the Source of Psychiatric Symptoms (Box 9)
    - Frequency of Convulsive Disorders in Feebleminded (Box 9)
    - Psychiatry and Rehabilitation, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - 1945
    - Emotional Factors in Illness (Box 9)
  - 1946
    - Feeblemindedness, Our Problem (Box 9)
    - Paroxysmal Convulsive Disorder Variants (Box 9)
    - Psychiatric Factors in Medical Students Who Fail (Box 9)
    - The Use of Modern Detention Screens in Psychiatric Facilities (Box 9)
  - 1947
    - Psychoneurosis (Box 9)
    - Psychiatry in General Medicine (Box 9)
  - 1948
    - Public Service Radio Announcement (Box 9)
  - 1949
    - Social Aspects of Hospital Administration (Box 9)
  - 1950
    - Prevention of Migraine Attacks by Dilantin Sodium (Box 9)
  - 1951
    - Psychiatric Aspects of Civilian Defense (Box 9)
    - Traumatic Neurosis (Box 9)
  - 1953
    - Epilepsy in Temporal Lobe Tumors (Box 9)
    - Sibling Rivalry (Box 9)
    - Practical Approach Successful at Disturbed Children's Unit (Box 9)
  - 1954
    - Steps in Psychotherapy (Box 9)
    - Initial Masking of Organic Brain Changes by Psychic Symptoms (Box 9)
  - 1955
    - Considerations of Temporal Lobe Phenomena (Box 9)
    - Focal Abnormalities of the Electroencephalogram in Juveniles with Behavior Disorder (Box 9)
    - Contribution to the Knowledge of Acute Brain Death (Box 9)
    - Michigan's Neuropsychiatric Institute (Box 9)
    - Intravenous Reserpine in Disturbed Psychotic Patients (Box 9)
    - Psychiatric Problems In Surgery (Box 9)
  - 1956
    - Counseling (Box 9)
    - Department of Psychiatry at the University of Michigan (Box 9)
    - Mental Health Public Service Announcement (Box 9)
    - UM Plan for the Residential Treatment of Disturbed Children (Box 9)
  - 1957
    - The Application of Psychiatry in General Practice (Box 9)
    - Psychomotor Epilepsy (Box 9)
    - Great Error of Our Day (Box 9)
    - When It Strikes Home (Box 9)
    - New Help For the Melancholic (Box 9)
    - The Value of Emotional Support and Environment Manipulation (Box 9)
  - 1958
    - Psychiatric Factors In Epilepsy (Box 9)
  - 1959
    - The Integration of Therapy (Box 9)
    - Narcotic Addiction (Box 9)
    - Psychotherapy of the Hospitalized Adolescent (Box 9)
  - 1960
    - To the Glory that was Greece and the Grandeur that was Rome (Box 9)
    - The Early Recognition of Behavioral Disturbances (Box 9)
    - Depression, the Simulator (Box 9)
  - 1961
    - Depression (Box 9)
    - Drugs and Psychotherapy (Box 9)
    - The Minister and the Psychiatrist (Box 9)
    - Psychiatric Factors in Medical Students in Difficulty-Follow-up (Box 9)
    - The Treatment of Drug Addiction (Box 9)